Somewhere inside all of us is the power to change the world.
Matilda is a comedy, family, fantasy film directed by Danny DeVito.
Matilda Wormwood is an exquisite and intelligent little girl.
Unfortunately, her parents, Harry and Zinnia misunderstand
her because they think she is so different.
As time passes, she finally starts school and has a kind
teacher, loyal friends, and a sadistic headmistress.
As she gets fed up with the constant cruelty, she begins to
realize that she has a gift of telekinetic powers.
After some days of practice, she suddenly turns the tables to stand
up to Harry and Zinnia and outwit the headmistress.
Matilda Wormwood, played by Mara Wilson.
Harry Wormwood / Narrator (voice), played by Danny DeVito.
Zinnia Wormwood, played by Rhea Perlman.
Miss Honey, played by Embeth Davidtz.
Agatha Trunchbull, played by Pam Ferris.
FBI Agent, played by Paul Reubens.
Matilda is a 1996 American fantasy comedy film co-produced and directed by Danny DeVito from a
screenplay by Nicholas Kazan and Robin Swicord, based on the 1988 novel by Roald Dahl.
The film stars Mara Wilson as the title character, with DeVito himself (who also served in a dual role as the
narrator and Harry Wormwood), Rhea Perlman, Embeth Davidtz, and Pam Ferris in supporting roles.
The plot centers on the titular child prodigy who develops psychokinetic abilities and uses them
to deal with her disreputable family and the tyrannical principal of her school.
Matilda was released in the United States on August 2, 1996, by Sony
Pictures Releasing under their TriStar Pictures label.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise being directed
towards its faithfulness to the novel and DeVito's direction.
Despite this, the film was a box office disappointment,
grossing $47 million on a $36 million budget.
However, Matilda subsequently attained greater
popularity after being released on home video.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, parent child
relationship, classroom, difficult childhood, child prodigy.
The tone is lighthearted.